[Music]
Hi everyone, this is Ravi. Welcome to
Tricentage Taska mobile automation
tutorial. As you all know, I have
already published five YouTube videos
covering different concepts of mobile
automation by using Tricentistoska. So
here is the playlist. I'm going to
paste the link in description. You can
access this playlist by using
description. And here is my first lesson
where I have showed you how can we get
started with mobile automation by
configuring Tricentis mobile agent. And
in lesson two, I've showed you how can
you set up Android emulator and how can
you install the Android Studio so that
you can create the Android virtual
devices. And then in lesson three, I've
showed you how can we prepare and
connect Android via USB and Android via
Wi-Fi. In lesson four, I've showed you
how can we scan Android mobile app by
using mobile engine of Tricentesa.
And in lesson five, I've showed you how
can we automate our first mobile test
case for Android. This is our lesson six
where I'm going to teach you how can we
scan native apps by using source labs
which means I'm going to show you how
can you integrate your tricentis taska
with source labs so that you can scan
your native applications
by using the real devices that are
available in source labs.
So here is our agenda for today's
session.
To scan your mobile applications from
the real devices available in source
labs, first you need to establish a new
cloud APM connection where I'll be
providing source labs server address and
then I'm going to add a device Android
as well as iOS device from SAS labs in
TUSCa and then we are going to add
Android app and one iOS app in Slab's
app management section so that I can
access those
Android and iOS applications from
Tricentis Taska. And then you need to
configure apps in TUSCa with bundle ID
that comes from your source labs. And
then we need to validate and edit
connections and device configurations in
Tentus Tuska. And now you can start
scanning your iOS and Android apps from
source labs.
So now without delay let us jump onto
the system and see how can we configure
or how can we integrate your tricentis
taska with source labs so that we can
scan the applications by using the real
devices available in source labs.
So this is my tricentis taska and before
we start scanning the application let me
show you my source labs account. So this
is my source labs account. I have logged
in with my credentials and you can see
here under live mobile app. So these are
the real devices that are available in
my source labs. So if you want to access
any mobile device, you can access these
mobile devices that are available in
source labs. I can access Google Pixel,
I can access Samsung Galaxy and I can
access iPhone XR and also I can access
iPhone 12. Right? So these are all the
mobile devices, real mobile devices
available in source labs cloud. Now
before we start scanning the application
by using these real devices, you need to
first go to app management. Here we need
to upload the APK file for Android
mobile devices and you need to upload
IPA file for your iOS devices. So if you
observe closely so this is your swag
labs mobile app which is related to
source labs. So the first file I have
uploaded the IPA file which is for iOS
device and my second file is my
APK file which is for Android device. So
how did I upload these files? Simply
click on choose file and I have selected
the source labsapk file slabsipa
file and clicked on okay. So this will
upload these two iOS and Android files
to your app management within source
labs. So this is prerequisite
to scan your application by using source
labs real devices. So I'm going to
provide all these details in the
description. If you need this APK or IPA
files, you can send me an email so that
I can send these files for you. So done.
So now we are ready with the app that we
would like to automate and now let us go
to mobile app and now let us go to
tricentis taska. So if you remember in
lesson three we have already showed you
how can you scan the application
by using tricentis mobile agent
where we have accessed either our real
device connected to my laptop or an
emulator that is running in my laptop
but in today's session I'm going to use
a device which is available in charlabs
cloud environment. So now for that right
click on these modules scan select
mobile.
So here if you remember correctly in my
previous sessions we have established a
connection called local and we have
established a connection called remote.
Now to access the device related to
source labs you need to establish a new
connection for your APM cloud. So for
that click on add connection and name
this as source connection
source labs
connect.
And here earlier we have selected TMA
for remote. This time I'm going to
select cloud APM because Slabs is a
cloud platform. Cloud APM platform. So
here you need to enter APM server
address. How can I enter that? Go to
your source labs and here you need to go
to account and then go to user settings.
Scroll down. Under user settings you
will have on demand URL. So you need to
copy this on demand URL.
Go to
present taska
here paste the on demand
server URL. But what you need to do is
here you need to delete the entire
content that is available
before
on demand. Basically from add rate till
here you can delete this one because the
taska throws an error saying that it is
invalid value. Right? So simply
I'm going to delete until here. Now the
URL is valid. Let's click on add. So
this is your new connection slabs
connection. Now I need to add a device.
For that go to slabs. Go to mobile app.
Here let's say I would like to add
iPhone XR. So select this one.
All you need is you need a unique ID for
this particular iPhone XR. For this
iPhone XR, my unique ID is iPhone
XR free. Copy this one. Let's go to
Tricent Taska. Here, click on add
device.
What is the name? I'm going to name this
as iPhone
XR. And what is your device ID? This is
my device ID. Paste the device ID. What
is this one? This is iOS. This is real
device. If you are entering Android, you
can select Android. Okay, let's add this
one. Let me add another device also.
This time I would like to add Samsung
Galaxy. I'm going to copy this unique
ID.
Go back to Tricent Taska. Add device.
I'm going to say Samsung Galaxy. And
here enter unique ID for that Android
Samsung device. But this time I would
like to select operating system as
Android. This is a real device. Click on
add. So now under SAS labs I have two
different devices.
Next
you need to add the application. To add
the application let's go to app
management under Slabs. So here let's
say first I would like to add Android
related application. So this is my
Android application. Go to settings and
app version. Check this one. So this is
my file name. So you need to copy this
file name from s labs and go to
tricentesto
add app.
What is the application type? This is my
native application. That's why I'm going
to select native. Click on continue.
Here enter the name. I'm going to say
coslabs_.
So this is my application name. And what
is the full path? My full path is
storage
colon
file name equal to. So you need to
remember this syntax. Storage colon file
name equal to your name of the
application which you have uploaded to
your source labs app management. So
simply paste that here and now select
the application type. My application
type is APK that means Android right and
now click on add. So my new application
has been added. So now let me scan the
application now. So here I have selected
the connection as slabs connection. I've
selected the mobile my Samsung Galaxy
mobile and then I have selected the app
just now I added which is your Android
file. Now select connect.
So it throws an error message. It says
failed serving request post. Why? Let me
tell you. Go back here now. So if you
remember correctly we have entered this
server address and we removed the front
part right. So there is a small bug in
Tricentis Taskar 2023 version. That's
why what we need to do is let us close
this scan. Now let's go back to your
triccent task. Here under
configurations.
Now if you go to mobile
under connection you see under
connections you should see the new
connection that we established. What is
the connection that we established?
Tasklabs connect. Under this source lab
connect if you expand
you should see the devices that we added
just now. iPhone XR Samsung Galaxy. So
now under Slabs connect if you see here
let me put it right side double click
here. See my APM server URL is not
correct. Let's go back to my source labs
settings user settings. So if you scroll
down here,
so this is my ondemand URL. Copy this on
demand URL. Edit this entire on demand
URL. I'm replacing it with the full on
demand URL which starts from which
starts from Ravikant E and your entire
URL. Now save this one.
So you understand right? So when we were
scanning the application when I'm
establishing the connection the time we
have entered the server URL as here from
here on demand us because taska taska is
having some bug. So I had to remove this
front part and now I have added that
front part from my connections
configurations.
Okay. So now let's scan the application
again. Right click on module
scan mobile.
So if you see the source labs connection
here edit see here now I can see full
URL now full server address it throws
error because there is a bug it is
throwing error message you cannot save
this entire IPM server URL that's why I
have done configuration from my
tricentis tuska configuration settings
so now I can see the full APM server
address. That's good. Now, this is my
Samsung mobile that I have added
from my source labs and then this is my
new source labs Android APK file. Right
now, let us click connect.
So now you can see connect connection
established device is connected. Go to
scan. You want to scan and click scan.
Okay. So here you need to click on scan.
As soon as you click on scan, it's going
to scan all the objects that are
available in your mobile. You can see
here you can see the Samsung Galaxy
device of your sabs also. So here I can
see here now. So this is your mobile
device from the Slabs.
Let's put this scanner here. So now
let's say I would like to capture
username, password, login buttons. Let's
select username
and you need to make it as unique
because this is not unique, right? The
selected item is not unique. Make
unique. So now it is uniquely
identified. Select password and this is
not unique. Make unique and then your
login image. Let's see what is this one.
Okay, let us select select on screen
here. Select on screen. This is your
login button. Highlight the section. See
this login section is now highlighting.
And let's highlight this username and
let's highlight the password. So all of
them are highlighting now. So now I have
scanned all the objects that are
required for login. And now let's save
this one.
So whatever the view you are seeing this
is your live view of your Slabs mobile.
What is the mobile? My Samsung Galaxy
mobile right.
So now
so now let's close the scanning.
So if you see here I can see now I have
a swag labs app related elements and
objects.
So this is how you can scan your
Android application by using the real
device from your source labs. So now let
me again scan. Okay I'm going to rename
this as mobile app Android. Okay. Now
let me scan one more time. Right click,
scan mobile. This time I would like to
scan the application
for my iOS device. What I'm going to do?
Select the connection which is Slaps
connection that we just now we created.
Right? And then this time select iPhone
XR. We already added iPhone XR. This is
my iPhone XR. Right? and iphone_xr
free. So let's see here. So this is your
unique ID. That's correct. Now this time
I would like to add the source labs
application related to iOS. Go to app
management. This is iOS related
application. Go to settings
and this is your file name. Copy this
one
here. Add app.
Select add application type as native.
Continue. Name this as iOS
tolabs.
And what is my full path? Storage colon
file name equal to
slabs dot slabs.ip.
This is my file name in source labs and
my operating system type is iOS. Click
on add. So now let us click on connect.
Now it should open your iPhone from your
source labs and you should be able to
scan all the objects related to iOS
application.
So now you can see connection
established, device is connected. Click
on scan. So this will open your iPhone
from your source labs.
So now you can see here it is your
iPhone. See this is my iPhone XR.
And in the same way simply select your
username
and then select your password. This is
uniquely identified and then select on
screen. Select your login button. Right?
All three of them are uniquely
identified. And you can highlight them.
This is your username, password, your
login button. So now let's name this as
mobile app iOS.
And now let's save this. So now you can
close the scan. As soon as you close
this close the scan your
live view of your device also going to
close. So now you can see this is my iOS
related objects and elements. So this is
how you can scan all the objects
from your real device deployed in source
labs or the real devices that are
available in source labs and this is how
you can integrate your tricentis taska
with source labs. So if you have any
queries leave your queries in the
comment box. I'll try to respond to your
queries.
Hope you all understand today's concepts
which is very very important because
these days all the organizations are
going for cloud solutions either you
might be using browser stack source labs
or tricentis device cloud any device
cloud platform. So you can follow the
same approach. So where we have
established a new connection for Slabs
cloud APM and then we have added devices
from your SAL labs and then we have
added
app for iOS and Android to SASLABS app
management and we have created the full
path by using the file name from your
SLAs's app management and then we have
connected
to your application
from SASLAB's mobile device and then we
have scanned all the objects that are
required for automating the test cases.
Please do subscribe to the channel,
click on bell icon, you'll receive
notifications whenever I publish more
videos and don't forget to like and
share the video. Thank you.
[Music]